and I got a bounty for it, a $1k bounty. My first bug, first bounty, so I was like oh this is
it's easy you know. I found with time that showing impact will result in better bounties
and also better bounties means higher impact. While still working full-time, I decided to apply
as a triager at HackerOne. And fortunately, I got the job. I think I'm always good technically
but OSCP gave me that mindset, that hacker mindset that I did not have. Sometimes you
won't get any error messages but you'll see that the application reacts differently depending on
your input. Hello Jr0ch, thank you so much for joining me today for the podcast. For those
listeners who don't know you yet, can you please introduce yourself and tell us a little bit about
your background? Sure, so my name is Jasmin Landry. It's a French-Canadian name. I'm known as
JR0ch17 on internet. Currently a full-time bug bounty hunter but I started my career in IT
in 2012, so almost 15 years now. My first couple of years in my career, I worked as a system
administrator so I worked a lot with Linux networking for like routing and switching
using like products like Cisco, Windows as well, Windows servers. I did a lot of certifications
as well. I was certified with Cisco, Microsoft, so VMware as well which was big 10 years ago,
not as much now. I did that for like roughly four or five years and after a while I was,
I wouldn't say bored, but I wanted more challenges. I wanted like something more challenging
and security was always something that I was interested in. At school, I had classes on
security but it was like really like basics and I wanted to, I guess work in security,
but I wanted to do more than just basic stuff. So obviously hacking or pentesting was something
that I always wanted to do. When I learned that we could do it as a job, I was like,
I want to do that one day. It's my career goal. So I worked my way to get there. So while I was
working full-time as a sysadmin, I spent my evenings learning, reading as much as I could.
I read many books on hacking and did a few certifications such as OSCP, which to me was
the game changer personally. I think I'm always good technically, but OSCP gave me that mindset,
like that hacker mindset that I did not have. Because as a regular person, you would just do
what the app tells you to do. But the OSCP helped me get the hacker mindset of like,
can I do something else that I should not be able to do? So I did the OSCP
and then after roughly six months after I got my first job in information security or
cybersecurity, I did stuff that were considered junior, but I got my foot in. So I was like,
okay, now I can focus. Was it more towards networking since you've already
had the experience with this? It did help landing a job in security, but I also did like it.
But I found it that it was not a passion. While cybersecurity, it was more of a passion.
I remember when I was studying, I had to like, okay, go to bed, it's late. While I was networking,
while I was studying networking, I did not have that passion. It was fun, but not like cybersecurity
or hacking in general. So when I got my job, I had colleagues who were pen testers. I was not
yet. I was just like a junior analyst. I did help them on some automation tasks or not automation,
but like running nested scans and stuff like that. And around that time, one of my colleagues
did a bit of bug bounty. He wasn't really good, but he was talking to me about it. He was like,
you should try it. I was like, okay, I'll try it. So I registered on both BugCrowd and HackerOne.
Tried, did not really succeed. What year was that?
2017. I did find one bug, which was like luck on a Microsoft application. I just put in a payload
and months later, I noticed that it worked. It was like a reflected XSS. And I got a bounty for
it. I got a 1k bounty on my first bug, first bounty. So I was like, oh, this is easy.
You learned from this guy as well.
Yeah. So this was like in February, 2017. So I literally got my first job, I think in January,
so a month earlier. So I started doing bug bounty one month later. And then for the next couple of
months, no bugs, no bounties, absolutely nothing. So I was like, okay, I need to take a step back,
improve my skills and more knowledge on the topics. So I did continue learning. I remember
having the HackerOne activity page open on my browser every day. So every day I looked at what
was reported, what was disclosed, read it. I looked at Twitter back then, X now, what people
were talking about where there were, maybe they were disclosing bugs or making public their
research or write-ups. So I read a lot. I read some more books on web application.
Do you remember the names of the books?
Yes. It was web application, Hacker's Handbook.
Yeah.
I think I read that one.
The Bible.
The 900 page book.
Yeah, it's a big one.
I think I read that one twice, actually.
Wow.
Because I think the first time I read it, I was like, okay, I understand. The second time I was
like, okay, now I get it. You only have like that, okay, I get it now. It's just like the time when
you think you're ready. So fast forward from February to August. In August, I found my second
bug, second bounty, another XSS. This one was a bit more complicated. So I was happy that I was
the first one on it because I put in the effort. So if it would have been a dupe, I probably would
have been discouraged. So I was first one on and got a bounty. And then the month after,
started finding more bugs. And I was not really, I wouldn't say like a good bug bounty hunter,
but I started finding stuff, had some dupes, obviously. So I was gaining confidence,
but I still felt like I was not where I wanted to be. I felt like I could improve myself even more
if I had the chance to learn more. So while still working full-time, I decided to apply
as a triager at HackerOne. Unfortunately, I got the job. So back then, I think this was December
2017. I worked at HackerOne as a triager for about a year, working 10 to 15 hours a week
on top of my full-time. Oh, so you do it like a part-time? Yeah, part-time. Okay, interesting.
Yeah. So by triaging reports, I learned that HackerOne does get a lot of reports.
Not always good, some really good, a lot of bad. We all know that. But I was able to,
I guess, learn. I would say like learn how others work because when we write a report,
we don't always write like how we got to that point. We just explain the bug. But it still
showed me like, okay, I didn't know, like, I don't know, PostMesh existed. So now I knew what that
existed, that it was runnable in some cases. So I was able to look into it, learn more about it,
and in the end, exploit it. So after a year of triaging, obviously, it's a job that's not easy.
So I figured, okay, I want to spend those 10 to 15 hours of triaging and do hunting instead.
So I started doing a bit more bug bounty in 2018. I had a good year while, again,
while still having a full-time job. So I probably did like 20 hours a week. Back then,
you know, I was like in my early mid-twenties, had lots of energy, and I was able to hack
late evenings. So I had a good year. I had met Joburg, founder of HackerOne, and
Peter Jaworski, who worked at Shopify back then. So I had attended my first LHC
live hacking event, which Shopify was actually in Montreal.
So I got my first LHC experience over there. I remember finding a few bugs, but they were all
closed as, I think, informative. Because Shopify is not an easy target. Especially as a beginner,
it'll be even harder. But again, I learned a lot while working with others, collaborating with
other people. The Chauvontel, obviously, was insane. I remember those bugs. Yeah,
the Chauvontels are critical to my learning anyways. And then, well, with time, I got
invited to more LHCs and stuff. And while I was working at HackerOne, obviously, I had access to
a lot of programs, right? So I was not able to hack on those programs because, obviously,
you would be cheating. So I hacked a lot on BugCrowd. My first couple of years
made my way in the top, I think, 40 at one point, all the time on BugCrowd.
And then switched to HackerOne because I think they were doing a bit more events,
and my friends were attending a lot of them. So I figured, I want to attend those too, right?
So I did a lot of hacking events, BugMonte, part-time as well.
And then a couple of years ago, during the COVID, I was a bit tired of my job.
I wouldn't say tired, but I eventually scaled up. I was not a junior analyst. I became a pen
tester, a senior pen tester, as a matter of fact. So I was hacking 40 hours a week,
and then doing BugMonte 20 hours, roughly, a week. So it was a lot. So I was like, okay,
oh, my brain is tired. So I took another job, which was not related to pen testing,
just an app tech job as a consultant for a six-month contract. So I could calm down my
hacking stuff, take a breather, and then still do BugMonte. But after a while, when I did
pen testing 40 hours and BugMonte on evenings, I wasn't motivated. So I wanted that motivation
back because I was really enjoying doing BugMonte in the past few years. So I took that job,
did it for six months. And then after the contract, I was like, okay, should I do BugMonte full-time?
Should I take another job? I was really debating. And it was roughly a year after I had my son.
And as a father, doing BugMonte full-time is a risk because we all know that it's not
stable income. We don't decide when we get paid. Well, with a regular job,
you get paid every two weeks, no matter what. So I was like, okay, I won't take the risk.
But it wasn't on mine. So I took a job in a startup in Montreal as head of IT and security.
So I was leading the whole IT department and security department. And the department was
me. I was alone. I was the very first employee in security over there in IT. So it was a startup
that was founded like 10 years earlier. So it was like a SaaS product,
which had barely any security. So even the employee side of things, there were no
basic stuff like antivirus on their laptops and EDR, there's nothing. So I was like, okay,
this is not what I was thinking of doing. But the challenge is so interesting that I'll take
the job. So I took the job and eventually hired more people, eventually put in the basics in place
just to get like a regular company would have as security products or whatnot.
And then a year later, we got acquired by NASDAQ, which was quite interesting because I learned that
the acquisition would not have happened because of my work.
If it had happened a year earlier, security would have been like an F on the audit for due diligence.
But when NASDAQ did the audit on the startup, we got an A plus on security. So I felt like really
cool. Even when you had the meeting internally where the founders were saying that, well,
we're going to get acquired by NASDAQ. I got a shout out saying, look, well,
you can thank Jasman because without him, this wouldn't be happening. So that was pretty cool.
And then while joining NASDAQ with the title that I had at the previous company,
with the work that I was doing, I got hired as a senior director at NASDAQ
in information security. So obviously NASDAQ was way bigger than what I was doing.
I had lots more departments, a lot more people in security.
So I stayed at NASDAQ for roughly two years. And then again, still doing bug bounty as a hobby,
part-time. Now as a family, I could even do less bug bounty, but still did like maybe 10 hours a
week on average, sometimes more, sometimes less. And then back in Vegas this past summer for the
Lifehacker1 event, I took two weeks off to just focus on the event itself. So I was like, okay,
let me just take some time for myself and hack. Just have fun. And I had a ton of my life.
I really enjoyed it. So I was like, okay, should I leave now? I was actually bug bounty full-time.
I was like, I'll think about it. And this is in August, the Lifehacker1 event in Vegas.
In September, I gave my vaccination. So I was like, okay, man, I think it's time. I'll give it
a shot. So yeah, so I left NASDAQ in end of September. So the first week of August, of
October, I was full-time bug bounty. Obviously it took some time off for myself. So 2024 was,
I mean, the rest of 2024 was a bit quiet. Did a bit of hacking, did a bit like recon building
just to get like some, I guess, passive income going, because I am like a deep dive hacker.
So recon is like not my thing at all. So I did a bit of building, a bit of hacking,
a bit of Hacker1 pentesting as well, just to like get back into it. And then starting in 2025,
I was doing like a full-time hunting and it's been doing, it's been going really well.
Yeah. I saw your Hacker1 profile. It's been really well.
Thanks. So yeah, I'm happy about that decision. I get to work. Well, work for me, it's not work.
I'm just having fun hacking, you know, but I do work a lot less than I did. I've been playing,
well, obviously as a Canadian, I play hockey. So I've been playing hockey a lot more,
even during like the work days. I've been playing golf a lot more as well. Golf is also another
passion that I've been building in the past year or so. So in the end, I work less and make more
money and have like more like free time for myself, for my family. So my son goes to school
now. So let's say he has a day off of school. Well, it's not a panic at home. I can just stay
with them, you know, and we can go out, we can go to the park and do anything we want.
Yeah, that's awesome.
Yeah. So if I need to take some time off, I just take it. I don't need to like ask for approval
or whatnot. So I find that it's a lot less stress, even though we don't get a stable income.
But in the end, the income is bigger, right? With bug bounty. Well, for me personally,
so I really less stress and I've been really enjoying it. So I don't regret it one bit.
Yeah, no, that's great. And also there's a thing that, because obviously a podcast about
bug bounty is about making money, but I really like this, these beats where somebody says
something about the workload balance, spending time with family. Cause I think this at the end
of the day, the, this is more important in your life than additional $2,000 additional five,
$10,000. And yeah, it's just invaluable and the time we will never get back. So,
so I'm really happy to, I, sometimes I try to sort of smuggle in the podcast like this,
but it's really hard. So I'm really glad to hear this from you.
Yeah. And like, so it's like really basic, like taking naps, like with a full-time job,
nine to five, you can't really take naps. And like, when I feel tired, I'll take a one hour
nap, you know, getting old. So, you know, I have to rest because I feel like sleep is really
something that I lacked the past couple of years. Cause you know, working full-time doing bug bounty
on evenings once in a while. So I feel like I need to catch up a bit. I think maybe it's maybe
the way I have a few white hairs in my beard now, maybe I like a sleep. So I'm trying to like,
you know, really work on my, my, my health work, like balance, make sure like I'm really
happy and healthy. And for now, I think bug bounty is perfect for, for me right now.
Yeah. Yeah, it is. So you've, you've mentioned a few different ways of learning. You've mentioned
books, you've mentioned just hunting. You, you've been employed as a pen tester. You've mentioned
some certificates, right? Which of these things, these methods of learning, you would say are
the most efficient in context of strictly bug bounty? I think it's really having your
like deep diving and working with it. I'm like a learner where having someone teach me
is I won't learn as much as I, as reading. For some reason, when I read, I learn faster and easier.
But having like really like testing stuff, I think is the way to do it to go.
Well, along with reading, for example, when at one point you will get stuck on something,
so you will have to look it up, which is equivalent to reading in the end.
So that's how I work in terms of learning. Let's say I want to learn something new.
I will like try to do it or whatever it is manually, and then read a bit on it and go
back to it. And, you know so for me personally, that's the, that's my way of learning.
Yeah, I see. And I think the, it's easy to, to get lost in different methods because they are
very satisfying. Getting a certificate, having a task done is very satisfying,
but I think just getting your hands dirty, it's the thing.
I think so too, yeah. For sure.
So I've mentioned, I saw your HackerOne profile recently. It looks really good with a reputation
of, with an impact of over 37 in the last 90 days, which is huge. It basically means you,
you have only crits.
Almost.
Almost. So what's the, what's the secret? What's, what's happened recently?
Um, I don't know. I remember like setting a goal for myself, I think for a long time.
Well, if you look at my overall impact all time, it used to be like around 20 something. I was
like, okay, I want to increase that, you know, cause it's always fun.
So I think now my impact, um, what is it all time? 25.95 all time.
That's good.
And it used to be like 20 ish. So like, I want to get, I want to increase that to
25. So like my average would be like the equivalent of a high.
Yeah.
So in the past year or so I focused mainly on highs and crits. Uh, if I found a low,
I would try to chain it with something else instead of reporting it as is.
Same thing for mediums. I did submit a few mediums, but I think mostly
highs and crits and even like for mediums, let's say reflected XSS. Um, I don't think I reported
one XSS, which was medium. I've always increased it to a high and even some cases critical.
Yeah. By basically taking over the account.
Yes, exactly. Um, and I found like, I won't say it's a new technique, but like,
it's just thinking of how to, uh, use the XSS to show impact. Um, so I, I won't say,
I won't say I've submitted only XSS, obviously not. I'm actually barely in XSS, maybe like
10 maximum, uh, throughout the year. But I did focus on highs and criticals, uh, on,
I did focus on how to maybe better show impact. Uh, for example, again, XSS as an example,
I used to just do like an alert, but I found with time that showing impact will result in
better bounties and also better bounties means higher, um, impact.
Yeah.
So in the end, um, showing impact on all of my reports, um, showing, I would say like,
um, focusing on certain stuff, cause I focus on everything. Um, but lots of server side issues and
I try to chain issues. So impact look for stuff that is a bit hidden.
Yeah.
Um, and in the end, well, I reported lots of bugs that were high and critical,
which increased my impact. And now it's just a habit. So let's say the night of 90 days,
like sharing is 37, but now it's like the way I work. Um, I look for, for stuff that
everybody looks for, I think, but I try to, you know, um, show impact a bit more than I used to.
Yeah. So what are your most common, commonly reported bad classes?
Uh, probably SSRF, um, as you guys saw or not yet, I have, uh, um, I reported an interesting one.
We published it on YouTube two weeks ago, the writeup we did together. So if you haven't
watched it, make sure you do cause it's an amazing SSRF with a huge impact. And it's also some,
some techniques of both the exploitation and detection that are probably universal across
more targets. So, so definitely worth, worth to watch that.
So yeah, SSRF for sure. Uh, one of my go-to, one of the bug classes I like to look for personally,
um, on all, on all kinds of applications, but I will not ignore other stuff like, um,
either server-side or client-side, whether it's XSS or CSRF, uh, path traversal,
both client and server-side, um, SQL injection, XSC, I'll look for everything.
Yeah.
Depending on what I see, um, uh, I'll look at it, but I tend to find more server-side stuff.
Um, like my client-side skills are limited a bit. Uh, so I will, I will, I will rarely find
anything related to the DOM, uh, like the XSS, I probably won't even look for it.
Yeah.
Um, but I use like the JavaScript to like find endpoints to look for server-side stuff,
for example. So I tend to find more server-side bugs, um, a bit client-side. Um, so yeah,
I'm a bit of a generalist, I'd say.
Yeah. When I was preparing for the interview, I also saw, uh, a big variety of different bugs
you, you report and also bugs that I ignore and I never look for them. So that's why I wanted to,
to interview, for example, server-side template injection.
Right.
It's, um, because for me, the problem of it is that in theory, it can be everywhere. So,
um, I don't know. And I don't like putting the payloads everywhere. If I don't have some
clue that the bug can be there. So what is your approach? Do you just have the,
the SSDI payloads everywhere, or do you look for some kind of clues that it can be there?
Uh, a mix of both. So I used to be like you were, I would not necessarily put payloads everywhere.
Um, at one point I was like working on an app, I had found absolutely nothing. And at one point I
put my payload everywhere and eventually it worked. Okay. Maybe I should put it everywhere.
So I started doing that, but the...
Sorry to interrupt. Which, which SSDI payload do you put? Do you have like a polyglot for all?
Not really. It depends on the app. Because certain applications, depending on language
that is used, the template engine will have its own syntax. So let's say, um, Python,
a template engine will be different than Java, PHP, Ruby. It's all different. So I try to focus
on, uh, what could be used in the backend. Um, for client side, I do have like more of
a polyglot because, because I have like a AngularJS view, which has a similar
syntax in terms of templates. Uh, but for server side, I try to be more specific.
Yeah.
Also to bypass a lot because a lot of cases they're, they're blocked like curly brackets
and whatnot. Um, so if you're a bit more specific, sometimes you can work around bypassing a lot.
Um, yeah, so yeah, that's my technique now, uh, specific, but I've put it everywhere because
I've had cases where, um, it worked and I was not expecting it.
Does everything also mean like a default headers, like user agent, like, I don't know,
host header or, or is it just inputs?
Just inputs. Yeah. Maybe you should try headers as you're bringing a good point, but, um,
yeah, just, just inputs.
Yeah. For me, I don't know. I feel stupid for not testing so many things, but
One thing I noticed, um, is some, a lot of applications, the way they're built these days
is your input will, is like on the application, but it will be brought elsewhere.
Yeah.
So, and those, sometimes those, those elsewhere will be vulnerable. So your payload may
trigger on that one.
Yeah. So like a second order, second order injection in this case.
Yeah. I kind of, I had a few cases like that, um, with Ansible, um, where I put in my payload,
like in my, my, in my email address and it eventually worked like in a total different
application. I put my, in my payload, like I think seven times seven, like the typical
test thing. Um, and then my email address, it was like JR0ch plus 49. I was like, wow.
And it was like totally different code, different everything. So something's happening
on the way there or over there. You're right. So, yeah, I've been just trying to put it
everywhere if I can, um, cause you never know where your input will end up.
Yeah. Do you have some kind of, I don't know, a word list that you always put in the, in
the payloads? Do you manually type it into each input? What's the, like, how exactly
do you, do you do it?
Uh, just like a match and replace rule. So I have like, um, uh, let's say I would put
SSDI and then the payload, it would be like my public lot for client side or, or another,
um, keyword, um, for server side stuff. Um, I use lots of, lots of, uh, match and
replace rules just to bypass like client side restrictions and whatnot.
Yeah. That's super nice. I never thought about this. I use, um, a sponsor, it's called,
but I don't use it enough, I think. And it does not, does not always work, especially
if you have some kind of weird input or whatever. So that's, yeah, I'm definitely going to use
this from now on. Another, the backlash I never find because I never test for it, SQL
injection. You have, I saw a Twitter picture from last year, from 2024, you had some, so
it's still around.
I found four more in 2025.
It still exists for sure. Um, I think like in the end for a SQL injection, even if you
have your database, like in, uh, AWS, uh, like you'd forgotten the name, um, but anyways,
or like in Azure, it's still in the end, the code that is vulnerable. So the developers still
code vulnerable code. Well, you'll still find some. Um, and so, yeah, so the ones that I found
this year were really simple. Like I just added like a single quote and see how it reacted.
Give me an error message showing that it's probably vulnerable. Um, and indeed it was,
and it's nothing that's really complicated. Like sometimes there are, they are complicated,
but the ones that I found, uh, in this year 2025, um, it's just like single quote,
send it to SQL map and the rest is done, you know, literally minutes of, of testing.
Yeah. Yeah. I think the exploitation part is the, the more doable one, I think the more
difficult to detect it. So I have a few methods of like testing, but something that is hard
is identifying the database that is used. Yeah. Sometimes like the, you won't get any
error messages, but you'll see that the application reacts differently depending on your input.
Uh, so that, that is usually hard to identify some cases, like the application is built on Ruby
on Rails. A lot of times it works best with Postgres. So we can kind of guess that Postgres
takes over PHP. It'll probably be MySQL, but you never know, right? It can be anything.
Um, same thing for like, um, apps built on, on C sharp or Microsoft products. So it will
most likely be, uh, MSSQL. But again, you never know. It can be anything, right? Yeah. Um, so
this is usually something that is quite hard. Um, I've kind of had a technique. It doesn't
always work, but sometimes it does, um, for identifying what is used in the backend.
And it's really simple. Just looking at like job applications or job offers. Sometimes they list,
like, oh, we're looking for a database administrator. This is what we're using. So,
okay, this is, they use that. So maybe it's, that's, that's what's used in the backend.
Um, so sometimes that's just a simple thing that can work. Um, so, so yeah, there's,
they still exist in 2025. Yeah. I saw, I saw, um, one of your, I think it was an article on back
cart that sometimes for a week on your browser job applications. And I was like, yeah, what
do you find in job applications? And yeah, that makes sense. Yes. I find that it's interesting
because when you look at an application itself, you'll see like language, like quick plugins,
like Mapalyzer built with and with error messages, you can see a bit what's used in the backend,
but it won't go in detail as much as like a job application. Yeah. Um, I find that some companies
have started like hiding that a bit, but some others like they'll show like, oh, Elasticsearch,
MongoDB, like they show everything what the developers need to know. And this is a good
indicator of what is potentially used in the background around that product. Yeah. Um, like I
said, like your input can go from like one app to the other, like let's say, uh, it can go from
the app to Elasticsearch, or maybe your data is stored in MongoDB and then a job fetches the data
from MongoDB and puts it in an admin dashboard. Like you never know. Right. Yeah. Uh, so knowing
what is used in the product or around, I think it's like an indicator or not an indicator, but like
it helps in terms of, of recon for me personally of what it could, what it could test for.
Also, one thing I saw in, in one of the interviews in the same blog post from Background was that
you think what infrastructure as a code use, uh, tools are used. And my question is first,
how do we even determine this? And the second is if you know what tools are used, how do you
use this information? Yeah. So this is like really context dependent. Um, so in, when I wrote that
article with Background, uh, it's cause I recently found an SSTI, uh, with Terraform where my input
landed in a Terraform, Terraform file. Okay. So, so Terraform evaluated my input. Okay.
That's a very specific functionality, isn't it? Yeah, it was. And in the end I could see that
evaluated it because it rendered it back to the application. Yeah. Uh, and with testing at the
time, I had no idea it was Terraform. Yeah. So I knew something was happening, but not sure what.
So with testing and all, I figured, okay, maybe it's a Terraform because I worked with it in the
past while I was working in AppSec. Yeah. I was like, is it that? So I tested it and indeed it
was. Yeah. Was this some kind of functionality, which was it like testing a cloud provider,
which allowed you to deploy some hosts, something like this? Uh, yes. So not a cloud provider,
but you could deploy, um, like products, like you can deploy like WordPress and stuff like that.
Yeah. Yeah. So, so context dependent. Yeah. So you won't probably, probably won't see that
like in regular applications, but again, if it's something that you can deploy stuff or
maybe sometimes not, it really depends. Uh, but something that I only found once with Terraform,
but I found this, so it exists. So maybe others. Yeah. And these targets are very interesting.
Like anything built for developers is very interesting. It is right. Exactly. Yeah.
Cause the functionality is very complex. The, um, what happens under the hood often like executes
comments, uh, creates clusters. This is very complex. This is very hard to get right. True.
And they may not think about the security impact or maybe you have some kind of separation. So they,
um, we don't need security because you have your own instance and then you have
a client side bug, which allows to do anything. And exactly from, from my, yeah, these,
these targets are very, very interesting. That's true. Uh, one other back cluster that I saw you
report and I also, well, sometimes I do test for it, but rarely, probably not often notice x, x,
z. Right. Cause this is very specific. I guess this is not a case where you spam the payloads
because you need like the XML parser to, to do it. But, um, do you have some experience of maybe
cases where it wasn't so obvious XML is parsed, but you through some trick, you made it parsed XML.
Um, not really. When I test for x, x, z is cause I saw something XML related. Yeah. But what I did
have luck with is look at features that people did not think XML was used. I had one case, um,
two years ago, I think, where, um, what was it again? I'm trying to remember here.
Um, but yeah, you could convert, uh, like a doc file or PDF to, uh, another file type. Yeah. And
one of the options was, uh, X lift file. What? Yeah. Exactly. It proves the point. So I looked
at what is an X lift file. So X L I F F. Okay. And by looking into it, it was XML. Okay. So
I just put like a regular exists payload and it worked. Um, how did you get to,
how did you discover a file like this exists? Uh, well, I mean, in the options on the UI itself,
on application, you could do like a doc, Excel, PowerPoint, regular TXT, HTML. And then the bottom,
there was X lift. Yeah. And so it's like, probably people tested for doc and PowerPoint
XL because it's a known technique where you can, well, it's a XML document. And yeah,
that is like compressed or zip, whatever. So people probably tested for that, but have they
tested? I mean, also probably tested from like HTML to other stuff, but how did you test for
X lift? And then you said what? So yeah, exactly. So I was like, probably not, you know? So I
tested it and it worked. I was the first time I didn't get a bounce for it. And yeah. So I look
for stuff where maybe people will not look or think the XML is used. Yeah. Um, I had another
case on that same application, um, in regards to, um, sitemap parsing, just a bit more of a
known technique where it's an XML file. So I had one case like that where you can give it like a
remote, um, sitemap file and it'll parse it. Um, and then XML. Yeah. Um, apart from that,
like it's, I won't necessarily put like, excuse me, pay those blindly. I'm just trying to find
a function that functionality or like other, um, other XML related specs. I've had luck with that
as well, where it's like format that is XML based and you can put XSC in there because it doesn't
expect it. I mean, the parser won't expect it, but it'll still parse it in some, some cases.
Um, so yeah. What do you mean other XML specs? Um, so like a one that I found recently,
I'm not sure if I can disclose the spec name. I guess the spec name is going to be anything.
Yeah. It's called CXML. Okay. I forgot what CXML is. We can look it up real quick.
Uh, commerce extensible markup language. And this is like one example, but there were
others that I found in the past, which, um, it was completely different spec related to, um,
I think like translation stuff. Okay. Um, and it was like, um,
XML based spec. Um, so I just looked at the docs online, see how it worked. Um, and then in the
end, maybe you can get an ecstasy with that because in the end it is XML. So maybe the parts in the,
in the backend will parse it, even though it doesn't look like, I mean, not that look doesn't
succeed. It's maybe a feature that others don't think there is XML parsing. It's not as obvious.
I see. Yeah. Yeah. Although now I thought about this probably spamming the payload
once every hundred times, it will probably work. It's crazy how many things we, we probably miss
as hunters in general, right. For like weird, weird things that happened that you can never
guess blindly. True. Uh, yeah. And one thing as well that has, um, that's happened in the past.
Well, I mean, recently is external. These don't work, but internal ones do.
What's an internal entity?
Internal DTD journal document. I forgot what it stands for document type definition, I think.
So in general, instead of pointing to like your own DTD file, you have to point to an internal one.
So I've had a few cases where external were disallowed, but internal ones did work.
So we have to test for both.
Yeah. Cause I guess there's one that's default in, uh, Ubuntu or Debian.
That's like, yeah. You have always these files available. Yeah.
Yeah. Cause it sounds pretty, um, cause the thing is you, you don't fetch the DTD from your server.
You need to know a local DTD, which sounds like something that's really hard to know
the black box test. Right. But there are a few that are in, I guess it was Debian
that it's always in the same directory and you can use the file protocol.
It's not like a guesswork. It's, uh,
Exactly. Yeah. Uh, and there are, um, I have a GitHub repo, not, I mean, not mine,
but like I started a GitHub repo that has a bunch of payloads containing, um,
I mean, internal DTDs. Yeah. That's pretty interesting. So I usually just use that list,
test it out. Cause in the end you're a black box, right. So you don't know what
OS is using the backend. Yeah. I've seen that. I think I remember
using these repo ones as well for, for something. Yeah. So for you to see, I keep in mind of
texting for internal DTDs as well, because I found that a lot of times, but sometimes,
like I said, by default, I think now more nowadays, um, by default,
they disabled external DTDs, but maybe forget about internal ones.
Yeah. Yeah. That's a good one. Good. These are, these are the bugs that were, uh,
that are painful for me because I know I miss them because I just don't test for them. I don't
know why, but, but, um, yeah, another bug that I do actually test for it, but I, I,
I want to test more because I see the potential secondary path traversal.
Yes. How, how, how has your experience with them?
One of my favorite bugs I tested for on every app that I, that I use, if I see that it's probably
happening, um, I, it's not something that I found often, um, but I do like looking for it. And, and
I think, um, it can be like a really impactful bug if you, if you're able to show impact.
Yeah. Um, it's funny cause when I was, when I started looking for that,
it's roughly the same time around, uh, when Sam Curry published his research about it.
And I actually, I actually DMed him. Have you seen this before? Cause I know this type of thing.
So it's like, Oh yeah, I'm actually doing a research on it. I published it like in the,
in the week or something. It was like really around the same time. It's like, Oh cool. I'll
just look it up. Um, and yeah, like I said, it's, it's, it's common. It's not something
that I found too many times, but I think it's sometimes a lot of times it's hard to,
um, I mean, it won't be verbose, uh, a lot. It'll show that maybe it's happening,
maybe not depending on the error message. Um, so there's a lot, lots of guessing work as well
needed if it's a bit blind. Yeah. Do you fast all the path parameters or all the parameters or what?
Um, I go a bit logically. Okay. Um, cause some parameters, for example, let's say it's like a,
an adjacent body of a post request. If the parameters like ID, um, let's say it's like a
digit, then maybe in the backend, if there will be like a call, let's say API V1 slash object name,
then the ID. Yeah. So maybe this is a good part of this. Yeah. If it's, let's say like a,
a parameter, this looks more like a metric related, for example, it'll have like your,
your Chrome version, for example, then probably not. I tried to go a bit more logically. Um,
but I, I would test every parameter that I, let's say, I'm not sure it's like really
specific to the application and I would test maybe all parameters to check because you never know.
Right. Yeah. Um, so yeah, that was my approach. Yeah. Cause yeah, it makes sense to basically
test every parameter that can be in the path later that this would make sense to test. So
most of the time it's going to be IDs, no? Right. Maybe a type. Right. And, uh, regarding to that,
um, I kind of discovered a new, I wouldn't say new technique, but something related to secondary
petroversal, uh, with GraphQL. Um, I'm going to talk about it, uh, at a future conference, but,
um, I think we need to keep in mind that it's not always just like an API, a REST API in the
backend could be something else. Yeah. Uh, so, uh, yeah, I think it'd be a fun. Yeah. The backend
can be really, really complex. I wait for, wait for the, for the full talk. Um, but yeah, we,
we sell many times that what happens in the backend can be crazy and that we don't expect
can happen. So, yeah, it's nice when you fast for the secondary because I guess for template
injection, usually you need like one payload, maybe two, three or four different engines,
depending on the technology for secondary petroversal. Um, how many payloads do you test?
Cause I guess you need different depths. I need, you need different, uh, iterations of,
of your own coding. So how long is sort of your, your world is for fuzzing?
Um, I actually rarely fuzz. I kind of do it like manually to see how he reacts. Okay. Um,
my typical go-to is like Trevor's back one path and comment out the rest. So I put like a question
mark or a hashtag, um, both with URL coding without depending on, on, on what's going on.
Cause a lot of times if you're not giving it, what is, what is expecting, it'll give you an
error message. Yeah. Um, so if you just like comment out the rest of the URL, maybe there
are hard-coded parameters that you're not seeing, uh, in the code and that in the error message,
it'll tell you all you're missing X parameter. Yeah. So that way you have an idea that, okay,
maybe there is like a departure muscle here. Um, or just like the path itself, but going back one,
it may say like, Oh, object X or whatever's going on is not there. So it gives you an idea of
something is, is, is happening in the back end. Yeah. Now you mentioned actually, cause I do have,
I do use a longer, longer list, but when I test manual, I would start with like going back and
going forward. Right now, I think actually you say it may be putting in a question mark
is more likely to give us a useful error rather than anything else.
So question mark, maybe the, the full URL is like your input then other path in the end. Right. So
if you put a question mark, it'll remove everything else. So it'll give an error message indicating
what is happening. Well, if you just put like, uh, uh, let's say the other slash or whatever,
without removing the rest, it'll just say maybe like not found compared to if you put a question
mark, it may be more robust. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. That's interesting. And also, um, if there is
some kind of filter for the dot slash, which I think is rare, but probably can happen. You're
not going to have problems with this. True. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Well, if, especially if the
input is in the body, um, obviously it depends on the wealth. Let's say Akamai is really annoying
with the slash, but other, but usually like you can get away with it with just with the regular.
Yeah. It's a body. It's not a problem, but sometimes you need to encode it. Um,
really depends on the context of the application. Yeah. So we mentioned GraphQL. Uh, I know the,
the research is, is coming later, but, uh, in general, what's, what's your methodology for,
for testing GraphQL? I guess you, you, you start by checking the introspection is enabled.
Yes. That's usually my, my first thing that I do. Um, I find that it's disabled most of
the time, unfortunately. Um, so what I do typically first is try to find the queries
themselves in the JavaScript files. Um, a lot of times they'll be there. I just look for like
query space. Yeah. Yeah. It's easy to prep for exactly. Um, or just like the operations name and
try to, to, to find, find those queries or mutations that way. And let's say I do have a
query, um, a valid query networks. I tried to add more parameters to it. See if I can
get those in response or disclose more information that I was not able to access.
Um, second year, Patrick Russell is also, uh, one that I've had success with in GraphQL
queries or, or mutations. Okay. Um,
so you would use the dot slash or whatever the character
variable as the variable. Okay. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Um, typical stuff like, um,
DOS, um, like normal technical techniques, technical hacking techniques. Yeah.
How successful are you with reporting the denial of service bugs?
When they mentioned that, um, not successful because everybody probably tests for it. Yeah.
Um, I actually started like not testing for it because I found that in impact, not always there
either. Uh, cause a lot of times it'll just like DOS, GraphQL service, everything else works.
And then, I mean, sometimes it's there, sometimes not depends on application,
but I just started looking for other, other stuff. Yeah.
Yeah. And also if you're testing the target, which you, you showed the right up from recently,
which has separate instances, sometimes you, you can only DOS if it's a post authentication,
sometimes you can only does your own instance. If, if, if that's a DOS and you have to be a
user of the organization, which you're DOSing at the impact is really low.
Exactly. Yeah. And yeah, and I had this case recently, I reported the denial of service
because the response time was really long. Um, and turned out that I could, even though
my instance was, uh, was, was having a long, long response time, the other instance was unaffected.
So even though it was like a very similar case to what you described, like the, the, the domain was,
was similar. So I assumed some resources are shared as well. Uh, it still was separated enough
that the DOS just didn't affect other users. So it was, it was pretty useless.
One thing as well, I just remembered, um, that I test for a lot of times the query will be in
the body of the request, but if you put it as a, as a get request, sometimes it'll work. So that
can help in terms of like CSRF or whatnot. Sometimes it works. And usually if it works,
it also allows mutations, doesn't it? Uh, I don't, I don't know. Maybe I haven't,
I think last time that I found it, it was only queries. Um, no, it was mutation because I
reported as a CSRF, so it did an action. Yeah. Yeah. I said that about the question,
I realized it doesn't really make sense. How about, oh, on the critical thinking podcast,
you mentioned, uh, a very interesting bug in don't purify. Can you please remind,
remind us or also the users didn't listen? What, what was the bug?
Yeah, sure. Uh, so it was a case, uh, where don't purify was used along with, uh, well,
obviously Chrome, um, and don't purify did block the meta tag, but for some reason it still, um,
existed in the DOM, I guess, in Chrome. Uh, so the bug itself was, um, I was able to leak,
um, an OAuth token by putting the meta tag, which, um, uh, what was it? The refer policy
so that the token would be sent through, uh, I think an image, I think I put an image payload
image tag, uh, as of my HTML injection payload. Uh, so that way the cookies would be sent to the
URL along with the token. Um, and from what I heard recently, uh, just last month,
that thing still works. So it still applies, uh, probably today. Um, I guess Chrome or number
don't purify has haven't not fixed it. So, uh, yeah, because, because the bug is that when your
HTML on the client side is being parsed, maybe you have, maybe you have a very restrictive
list of allowed tags and usually meta tag will not be allowed usually. Yeah. But, but still after
parsing it, it is applied to the website. So even though don't purify the HTML, it's still in the
website. Right. Yeah. Yeah. That's a very cool bug. I stumbled on it like a bit by, by chance,
cause I literally just trying any payloads, um, thought of meta of meta tag, cause it did apply
to my, to my scenario. Yeah. Um, and I later learned through, um, critical thinking of how
to look for the allow listed tags and don't provide. So I did not do that last night,
which was really just like trying some strikes on stuff. Yeah. Um, and yeah, like I said,
ended up working and, and still works to this day. So even if Dumpurify blocks it,
yeah, it's still, for some reason applies, uh, in the DOM. So, uh, yeah. So if you have
don't purify on the client side and you have something sensitive, you can put in the URL,
use this cause it still works. So it's a very interesting bug. I'm trying to think if I have
some target users, maybe because Dumpurify is used a lot more than it used to be like just
two or three years ago. I feel like now it's everywhere. Yeah. I think it became the standard,
which we should be happy about at the end of the day, but as bug hunters, we, we're not,
which means they do a good job of being hard to bypass. That's true. Um, speaking of, uh,
of oath. So if we have, um, this bug, which allows us to, to, to, to leave the URL.
Um, but for, for this to, to be a valid attack, we have, we should put an unused code in the URL.
Right. So what are some methods we can do it with? Um, so when I test for a lot, I find it
like so many attack scenarios and techniques. So I usually just like open up, um, Franz Rosen's
like duly dancing article, which is great. Just trying to think of like, okay, I should maybe try
this and that. Um, I also look at the, like, I think there's a guide for all was, um, hiking,
like created from a WASP, I believe. Um, sorry. Oh, well, I can go. Yeah. Um, so look at that
for like ideas. Um, but a lot of time, I just look for the basic stuff. Like, can I send the
code to, uh, attacker server attacker on server to do a direct URI parameter? Um, it's the state
validated. Um, what else? What am I, what am I missing in terms of, uh, the basic stuff? Yeah.
Yeah. I, I remember after the article from France, I started testing the flow,
right. But I, I got to a point where usually it's, it's, if there's, uh, the old flow,
it's fairly easy to break it and to, to lend with the code on the page. The,
the, the harder part is to leak this URL. Yes. So, um, usually it means needing an XSS
or the bug you mentioned, or the one he described was some kind of XSS, but on a sandbox domain,
but it allowed to, to leak the URL, but it's usually quite difficult to do.
Unfortunately. Yes. Yeah. And then like I said, you need an XSS, but you don't have an XSS. So
you don't often, I don't always need to exploit that part to do something bad. So exactly. Yeah.
You can, you can probably use it as a gadget to show the impact of XSS. If you can address it,
change the email or stuff like this. Yes. Uh, actually remind me of something. One thing that
didn't work recently is, um, something that Dorian sick, um, published recently. And I think
also Justin spoke about it and critical thinking. Uh, I think they call it client side, no client
application confusion, confusion, something like that. Yeah. Um, actually I think I pulled it up
here. I wanted to remember that. I want to talk about it. Yeah. The blog post from the, I think
about it. Yeah, I actually don't. So, yeah. So, um, you can create like your own, I mean, if you
can, depending on the context, use like different client ID, sometimes they won't validate the
client ID, but once it's time for the, for the application to validate the token, it'll notice
that it's not, um, uh, for the client. And, um, so the token will not be consumed. So you can try
to steal it in another way or not, but there are ways by manipulating the client ID where you can
get access to the token or, you know, lots of testing to be done with, uh, with a lot. Um,
and also I remember one bag and I sort of tracked the origin of why it was possible
because it was possible to use like my client to authenticate to somebody's instance. Right.
It was using Cognito. Okay. And I tracked back that in the AWS documentation, there was, or still
is, I haven't checked a code snippet to, to validate the token in that case. And this code did
not have, because basically what you need to do in, um, in that case is to validate the issuer.
If it's the one you're trying to authenticate user against and basically the code in the docs
didn't have this, this validation of the issuer, but the doc said, this code does not have the
validation of the issuer, but for the production code, you should do it yourself. But of course,
but of course the developer would copy the code and use it as is. So, so, so we do work like this.
I think they did fix this part in the documentation, but it was very kind.
I also remember one OAuth bug from a show in South Africa where it was, uh, recently,
I remember it was, I was mad seeing that cause I had something that I had tested for,
um, in the old flow, the product, I mean the application, there were like custom parameters
that were added in the old flow. Yeah. And I was like, it's probably just like metric stuff,
like for, for them to know, like who connected from where, uh, it turns out that by manipulating
those, those, uh, parameters, you could just put any redirect URI and the token would be
redirected over there. So since the custom parameter had like arbitrary data, it like
did a dirty dancing and messed up everything. So yeah, it was one case where I was like,
oh, I should have thought about that, you know? Wait, so another parameter was used as a redirect
No, I mean like another parameter was part of the old flow. Yeah. It contained like, uh,
I forgot what it was. Um, but just like something that not necessarily part of like the old spec
and the regular old flow, just like an arbitrary, like parameter specific to the application.
Yeah. I see. And by manipulating it, um, you could put in any value as you redirect your
parameter. It could redirect the code anywhere. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. That seems, yeah. I always
love to see the, the custom parameters or, uh, when the state is like a Jason, I love to see
when there's like the, uh, P K C E thing or the challenge, uh, just remove those parameters.
Sometimes it works, you know? Yeah. Yeah. Um, how successful have you been recently with like
the typical old redirect URI takeovers where the redirect URI just isn't validated properly?
Um, it's been a while. Um, I think the last one was through like a past reversal in the
redirect URI. Yeah. So it stays on the same application and same origin, but you did an
XSS or something or like a HTML injection with the metal tag, whatever, another technique to
redirect. Yeah. Um, but it's been a while. Um, I found like, uh, I think a few last year,
but I don't think I found one yet in terms of joy from regress or lots or
yeah, it's hard. Programs are starting to configure it a bit more properly, but I think
there's always some, some weird bugs laying around and all that. So yeah, yeah. Of course
there's, you have some hidden parameters. Yeah. It leads to that are just forgotten.
And the validation is like, I suppose, you know, it reminds me of one bug actually.
And it's quite interesting. Um, and part of the overflow, like I manipulated the scope part
and I added myself a privilege that I usually did not have. Yeah. And in the end it was redirected
to arbitrary hosts that I did not even know existed. Yeah. Because of a different scope.
Right. And it gave me like, you're not allowed to access that permission, but it was the token
was sent in the URL and the other host. So I just like found another XSS on that other host
and then was able to look at the token in the old flow. Yeah. That's interesting. Yeah. It was,
that one was weird. Yeah. Because why would it redirect to a completely different host?
Like what was the other host? Was it like a, it was like some kind of SSO server,
but it was not used. It was like used for another product. Yeah. Yeah. That's cool.
It's like, and usually it was, it was like in the login or like some kind of SSO, but usually like
in the login application. Yeah. But that one was sent to completely different one, which was not
even used as like a lot for my application. Yeah. Yeah. I see. Do you often test for, let's say,
lower severity of related bugs where, for example, when you go through the authentication
flow with some restricted set of scopes, and then you want to redo the authentication flow,
but with more scopes, it should re-prompt the user to confirm the new scopes.
So if there's no reconfirmation, it's like a lower medium level bug. There are a few different
ones as well. I know Johan is sometimes looking for bugs like this. Do you also spend time on this
or because of your resolution to look for highs and creases? Yeah, not really. Maybe I should,
maybe it could lead to like more bugs and more interesting bugs that can be achieved with other
stuff. But yeah, I usually just try to link the code somehow. Yeah. Because it directly leads to
ATO, right. So, which is my goal for OAuth. Yeah. For highs and creases. That's the only goal.
Because I have started recently to hunt, because I hunted on the target that paid really well
for mediums. So I also hunted for these attack scenarios that are a little bit more difficult
to exploit because the attack scenario is like the app is the attacker. So it has more privileges
than it should, and it's clearly a bug, but the attack scenario is not there. But on a good target
that pays up to 1000 lows and up to 8,000 mediums. So that's worth it. Yeah. Awesome.
And I think there's a lot of bugs like this, but it's quite difficult to test.
But sometimes it is worth it. Okay. Last question. Because you said that you're more like a deep dive
guy, more like a manual hacker, but you did build some automation. So what does the automation do?
It's pretty, I wouldn't say simple. I don't do any nuclei hacking or scanning because I feel like
everybody's already doing it. So it would be a waste of resources and time to do it.
So I have put an infrastructure in place where I get alerted when a new app has been put online.
Okay. From the DNS sources? Yeah, DNS. So sometimes it resolves. Actually,
a lot of time it doesn't resolve, but at least I know when it's there. And I put a bot in place
that would constantly test the disillusion... No, sorry. Let me start again. So I have a totally
place where it alerts me of new assets, whether they're on the internet or not. Sometimes it
resolves, sometimes it doesn't. If it does resolve, I'll do like HTTPS on it, see if
HTTPS is running. If it doesn't, just store it in the file. And then the bot that I built
will constantly do a disillusion. I mean constantly, once I think every week that I did it
to see if it does resolve. And if it does, then do HTTPS. Okay. Yeah. Do you somehow note all
the domains that resolve to internal IP addresses to use it later for SSRs? I do store it
but I don't go back to it much. I go back to it when I do need it for an SRS. Yeah.
Yeah. Because I thought it's useful to, let's say we have loads of IP addresses resolved from a
wildcard domain, let's say. It's useful to just save all the internal ones. And once you have
the SSRs, that's the ones that you use. Exactly. So that's what you do. Yeah. Nice. Yeah. I thought
about it but I didn't do it. Yeah. I think in the end, I kind of changed my technique a bit.
Yeah. So I used to just like open verb, hack, that's it. Now I've been gathering a bit more
data, taking a lot more notes. My notes are a lot more structured. Oh. And I do note
internal domains and take note of everything that I see that can lead to a bug.
So I think I probably missed some bugs in the past where I was like, oh, I remember that,
but where was it? I don't know. But by taking notes, sometimes it's easier to go back.
How do you organize the notes? I have like, let's say a hack on one application because
and I did that, so I don't really do recon or not much anyway. I have like technologies used,
like my recon in terms of hacking on an app. Not like scanning, just like recon on the
application. So I'll note technologies used. I'll note the API endpoints,
the reverse proxy API, sometimes like slash, I don't know, water will have a different
backend than another one. So I know like which one leads to another backend.
Sometimes like slash water will have like an own JS app, but slash glass will have a Java app. So
I take note of all of this, take note of GraphQL endpoints, things that I notice that are like
interesting or weird. Sometimes just something as simple as like a metrics, like slash metrics
endpoints are pretty useless. Usually if you report them, it's going to be like informative,
but it can help in other stuff. So I take note of that. I take note of like lows and mediums that I
will not report, but can be trained with something else. I take note of what I see
is interesting and what to test. Kind of like a bit of modeling, like, okay, this app has this,
a bit of logic behind like what to test. And actually could probably take a look here.
Yeah. So the things you save for later. So internal domains, obviously lows, mediums,
that you can potentially change with something. What else are like the typical things you sort
of save for later? Stuff that I find that are probably vulnerable, but have a hard time
exploiting or that they disclose information, which can probably help in another place.
For example, I had one case where when I uploaded a file for some reason, once in a while, it said,
oh, cannot find file in this path. This was the internal path. So I could know where it was being
uploaded and maybe I could do like a patch reversal and upload it elsewhere or whatnot.
So information like that. I also store custom headers. I've had a lot recently with like
custom headers that the companies use. Success in what sense? In the sense of
putting one header in a different request that normally did not have that header?
Yeah. Sometimes, yes. I see, I saw different behavior. And one trick as well that I think
France, obviously France knows everything, right? It's looking at the access control
allowed headers, I think, in response. Sometimes you have like custom headers in there and putting
them in the request will have an interesting behavior. So I had a few cases like that,
which was interesting. I was not always able to exploit it, but I know something is happening.
They're doing something with that header. Well, I didn't get this part.
I mean, the headers that are disclosed in the access control allowed headers,
sometimes you have a bunch of them. So if you put one by one or all of them in your request and put
any value, sometimes the application will reply with something interesting.
Okay. Yeah. Okay. I see. That's interesting.
And also cases where the app used custom headers for admins. And by putting that header
in the request and putting like a, let's say it was like a X dash user ID in the request,
I could put another ID. It got me access to another users. Yeah. Something like that.
Like, yeah, that's cool. So that should not work, but it works.
After speaking of things that should not work, but they work or they worked after the recent next
JS bug, I'm tempted to just take a look at the source code of each web framework,
just the correct for all the headers. I thought about that too. Yeah. I actually
thought about it too. Yeah. Cause I'm sure something weird happened. There must be something
else. There must be something else. It's not the first time that that guy in particular has found
next JS bugs specific to headers. I think he had found two or three regarding to cache poisoning
and now an authorization bypass with headers. And I think I found a few too, where it led to some
interesting stuff. So I think headers are definitely an interesting attack surface.
Yeah. Yeah, for sure. We'll end our interview here. But before we do, tell me what, what are
your plans for 2025? Is this is your first full year as a full-time Bug Bounty Hunter.
What are your goals for this year? I have my financial goals in terms of Bug Bounty.
I'm on pace to pass that. I think by a lot, if I can continue hacking and finding more bugs.
I'm hoping to get invited to a few more life hacking events because those usually boost a bit.
And I'm hoping to take more vacation as well. I actually go on vacation a couple of weeks. I'm
hoping to be able to, to schedule some, some more later this summer, maybe in the fall as well.
We'll see, you know, just have fun, play more golf, hockey and have fun doing multiple time
or part-time, but like full-time. Part-time is full-time. Awesome. I wish you a lot of good
luck with this and thank you so much for the interview. Thanks for having me.